Guide to the Dan Nimrod papers, 1938-2002 MS2192
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Biographical Information - Nimrod, 1938-2000; MS2192 Series 10; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains biographical information on Dan Nimrod. It includes copies of Nimrod's credentials for various organizations to which he belonged, biographies of him in various publications, and his newspaper columns from when he wrote in Israel in the early 1950s. The material dates from ca. 1938-2000. The Israeli period columns are in Hebrew with English translations of the titles.
  - Biographical Information - Dan Nimrod (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dan Nimrod - Literary Activity: the Israeli period, 1951 ca.-1955 -- --ca. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Dan Nimrod - The One Man Zionist Hasbara Campaign (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Eine Stimme fur Gerechtigkeit - in German, 03/07/1994 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - George Washington University - Address by Dan Nimrod at Dedication Ceremony, 11/29/2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - George Washington University - Jewish Press, 05/12/2000 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - George Washington University - Reception in Honor of Dan Nimrod, 11/29/2000 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Identity Cards and Certificates Related to Political Activities, 1938-1966 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Sol Modell, papers, 1968-1995; MS2192 Series 11; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains the papers of Professor Sol Modell (1915-98), a correspondent of Dan Nimrod's whose papers went to Florida Atlantic University and subsequently to GWU as part of Nimrod's donation. The bulk of the material dates from 1968-95. It includes letters and newspaper clippings from Modell, largely related to Israeli politics and foreign relations, but sometimes to other issues as well. Modell, a professor at Los Angeles Valley College, was a columnist for Heritage, a Jewish newspaper in Los Angeles, and wrote to many individuals, mostly in the United States.
  - Papers:, 08/1968-07/1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Papers:, 08/1976-12/1977 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Papers:, 01/1978-01/1980 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Papers:, 02/1980-09/1980 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Papers:, 10/1980-07/1981 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Papers:, 08/1981-04/1982 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Papers:, 05/1982-01/1983 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Papers:, 02/1983-02/1984 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Papers:, 03/1984-10/1984 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Papers:, 11/1984-05/1985 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Papers:, 06/1985-12/1985 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Papers:, 01/1986-12/1986 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Papers:, 01/1987-12/1987 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Papers:, 01/1988-07/1988 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Papers:, 08/1988-11/1988 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Papers:, 12/1988-06/1989 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Papers:, 07/1989-06/1990 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Papers:, 07/1990-02/1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Papers:, 03/1991-07/1991 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Papers:, 08/1991-10/1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Papers:, 11/1991-03/1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Papers:, 04/1992-09/1992 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Papers:, 10/1992-02/1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Papers:, 03/1993-07/1993 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Papers:, 08/1993-11/1995 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Incomplete Material (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Undated Material [1/2] (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Undated Material [2/2] (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Ephemera, 1977-2002; MS2192 Series 12; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains miscellaneous videos and audiotapes donated by Nimrod. It also contains a plaque from George Washington University to mark Nimrod's donation of his library in 2000. It includes an oral history with Yedidiah Blumenthal, a longtime Zionist activist in South Africa, and other documentaries selected by Nimrod to be included with his archives. Most of these documentaries pertain to the Arab-Israeli conflict and other Jewish issues.
  - Zionist Revisionist Organization - S.A. - Jedidiah Blumenthal - Retirement [South Africa - Correspondence] (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Mark Langfan - Shalom America, 02/13/1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Benjamin Netanyahu's Address - 12th Anniversary Dinner of the Holocaust Memorial Center, 10/29/1995 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - The ANC Method: Violence (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Israel Today: The Impact of the Peace Process on Democracy & Dissent (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - 1. Golan Heights 2. 9 Narrow Miles 3. Strategic Equation (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Frank Eiklor Reports: "Interview with Leonard Horwin - As it goes with Israel...", 02/10/1993 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - The Weider Brothers Men of Iron- Life & Times (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Entrevues de Ben Weider, Ron Corey et le Cardinal Turcotte par Francois Faucher (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Unknown Video (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Plaque, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 1)